Joey Hardy

Sr. Software Engineer



Technical Skills

Skilled in architecture, problem analysis, and technical development, with emphasis on parallelization, best practices and efficient delivery

Interested in practical functional programming and

Technologies Proficiency in MERN stack. Wide experience with other technologies and always interested in learning and expanding skills

Tools Experience with Git/Github, Jira/Bitbucket/Bamboo, TFS and other project management systems

Frameworks Comfortable with various frameworks and libraries, including React, Node.js, Mocha, Express, and Wordpress

Work Experience:

2015-present Team Lead/Senior Developer, Taillight, LLC, Addison, TX

- Lead a team of developers to create systems for handling orders and subscriptions, with integration to third party tools such as Stripe and Shopify
- Spearhead efforts to learn and develop better automated testing practices as a team
- O Develop devops tools, define CI/CD strategy for Bamboo build and deployment plans and create framework for templating new API and frontend Next.js projects
- Architect and plan new features, large scale refactors and maintenance for tech debt. For example, plan and execute an effort to replace all customer's devices due to the national 3G network sunset in less than a month
- Mentor junior engineers. Lead efforts to develop skills and knowledge for entire department

2012-2014 Enterprise Systems Developer, Navigation Solutions, Plano, TX

- Developed embedded systems GUI/backend using third-party UI framework and proprietary data backend for GPS devices rented in Hertz rental cars. (C++, XML, SQLite, Python)
- Created and maintained SOA web services for use by websites, mobile apps and the GPS devices over cell network. (C#, Javascript, MS SQL, HTML/CSS)
- Created Android and iPhone apps which take advantage of the web services we provided for online trip planning. (C# mono, Obj-C)

2009-2011 Online Web Developer, D Magazine Partners, Inc., Dallas, TX

- Implemented interim custom CMS solution tailored to fit company needs. (C#, SQL)
- O Began developing long-term solution using Umbraco, a .NET-based MVC framework.
- Maintained and created new Wordpress-based blogs for different areas of interest, such as Dallas happenings, home design and fashion. (PHP, Javascript)
- Translated designer's creatives into markup and code (Javascript, HTML, CSS)
- The website earned the City and Regional Magazine Best Website of 2012 Award.

Open Source Contributions

WistiaKit

Added hooks to iOS/TvOS library to enable consumers to cache retrieved media information.

Education:

2006-2010 B.S. in Computer Science, University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX